# Shelley McHardy Atlanta, Georgia

Phone: 404-405-4045 | Email: shellevmcq.dev@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/shelleymchardy</u>

GitHub: <u>github.com/shelleymcq</u> Portfolio: <u>www.shelleymcq.dev</u>

Software developer with a background in science education, motivated to leverage tech and teaching skills to create modern applications and experiences for learners and information seekers, and to make the web, and world, more beautiful and accessible.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, Redux, TypeScript, Optimizely, Cypress

#### **PROJECT SAMPLES**

**Smart Shopper** | Repo: <a href="https://github.com/the-collab-lab/tcl-36-smart-shopping-list">https://github.com/the-collab-lab/tcl-36-smart-shopping-list</a> Deployed: <a href="https://tcl-36-smart-shopping-list.web.app/home">https://tcl-36-smart-shopping-list.web.app/home</a>

- A shopping list app designed to learn how often you buy items and to keep you organized.
- As a member of a 4-person team with the Collab Lab, primary contributions were styling, displaying list items, and leading the team for the final self-directed weeks of the project.
- Developed using React, Firebase, and TailwindCSS.

**Temperature Visualization** | Repo: <a href="https://github.com/shelleymcq/temperature">https://github.com/shelleymcq/temperature</a>
Deployed: <a href="https://temperature-ivory.vercel.app/">https://temperature-ivory.vercel.app/</a>

- A tool for crafty users to find the high temperatures for a given US city in a particular year.
- A personal passion project that I've used myself to create special gifts for my mother and family friends. It's an easy task to get daily temperatures, but this app uses the NOAA Climate Data Online API to find historical temperature data for an entire year.
- Developed using NextJS, React, and TailwindCSS.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Associate Software Developer**

6/2022 - 3/2023

Rightpoint (remote)

- Created scripts in nodeJS that automated i18n tasks and saved developers time.
- Implemented new features to React/TypeScript codebase such as list virtualization.
- Reviewed PRs, fixed bugs, CSS to match app design, git version control in an Azure DevOps repo, wrote Cypress tests and documentation.
- BigCommerce certified.

## **Teaching Assistant & Mentor**

11/2021 - 4/2022

2U, Georgia Tech Full Stack Flex Coding Bootcamp (online)

- Supported instructor and mentored students via zoom and slack.
- Managed course repo on Gitlab, reviewed and graded student projects.
- Assisted individual and student groups as they learned web development with JavaScript, APIs, various libraries, frameworks, and the MERN stack.

# **React Developer Apprenticeship**

1/2022 - 3/2022

The Collab Lab (remote)

- Worked with a team of four to build a project using React, Tailwind CSS, and Firebase.
- Focused on collaboration based on Agile methodology, pair programming, code reviews, weekly retrospectives, and git version control.

## **Science Teacher**

10/2010 - 5/2021

Gwinnett County Public Schools, Lawrenceville, GA

- Taught chemistry, forensics, and physical science to middle and high school students.
- Designed and presented workshops to teachers in topics ranging from building relationships with students to integrating technology in the classroom.

## **Chemistry Teacher & Curriculum Developer**

8/2003 - 6/2010

Oakland Unified School District, Oakland, CA

- Taught chemistry to high school students.
- Served on the county team to develop chemistry pacing guide and benchmark assessment, and as a new teacher mentor.

#### **VOLUNTEER**

**The Collab Lab**, https://the-collab-lab.codes/Board Member, Career Lab Manager

• Coordinate participants, presenters, and volunteers, schedule events, maintain repo.

Virtual Coffee, https://virtualcoffee.io/

Lunch & Learn Coordinator

• Coordinate presenters, schedule events.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Bootcamp Certificate**

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, Georgia

A 24-week intensive 2U program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, Jest, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, ReactJS, MVC, and MERN stack.

# **BA in Physical Sciences**

University of California, Berkeley, California

Completed core courses in chemistry and physics, as well as electives in computer programming, nuclear energy, atmospheric chemistry, and environmental data analysis.